EVAN MISSHULA

http://Misshula.org EMisshula@jjay.cuny.edu (917) 975-7039

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I have published original research in four areas of statistics including machine learning, time series, social networks and spatial statistics. Additionally, I have fluency in web application development, operating systems security including penetration testing and interactive data visualization.

EDUCATION

PhD Criminal Justice (ABD) City University of New York, New York, NY August 2015 (expected)

BS Applied Math (Operations Research) and BA Economics & Mathematics *Yale University*, New Haven, CT

May 1988

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

"A Reexamination of Connectivity Trends via Exponential Random Graph Modeling in Two IDU Risk Networks," in Substance use & misuse. 2013.

"Network sampling of social divisions in a rural inuit community," in *Identities*. 2012.

"Estimating the Size of the Methamphetamine-Using Population in New York City Using Network Sampling Techniques," in Adv. in Applied Sociology. 2012.

"Dynamics of Methamphetamine Markets in New York City," in Final Technical Report to the National Institute of Justice. 2011.

CAREER HISTORY

Statistical Analyst, CUNY John Jay Research & Evaluation

July 2012 - Present

- Responsible for designing statistical tests for a wide variety of projects
- Created web mapping tools using d3, TileMill and Leaflet
- Evaluated anti-violence program using DiD and spatial statistics

Data Science for Social Good, University of Chicago

Summer 2013

- Developed neighborhood and property analytics software for Cook County Landbank delivered as a Django/Python application
- Integrated mapping, economic and demographic data

RF CUNY, CUNY

February 2010 - May 2013

- Conducted original research on public health and criminal justice issues including prison simulation, suicide, domestic violence supported by NIH and NSF.
- Conducted original research on detecting causal relations supported by CUNY Advanced Research Collaborative.

SKILLS

Languages: R, Python, JavaScript, LATEX, Ruby, Swift, C, C++, Java

Libraries: D3.js, Leaflet.js, ggplot2, Django, Rails, Postgres, Pig, Hadoop

AWARDS AND HONORS

Fellow, Insight Data Science	$Summer\ 2015$
CUNY GC Digital Fellow, CUNY Graduate Center	2014 -2016
Provost's Digital Initiative grant winner, CUNY Graduate Center	2013 -2014
Steven and Elly Hammerman ethics across the curriculum, CUNY John Jay	2012
US Cyberchallenge student fellow, Eastern Regional Camp (Virginia)	2011 & 2012
DHS Data Science Summer fellow, Univ of Illinois, Urbanana-Champaigne	2010
PhD fellowship, CUNY John Jay	2009 - 2014
Sunshine Scholarship. College Initiative	2009 - 2014